《越狱》前情回顾
Previously on prison break
是的 请帮我接通11频道的新闻热线
Yes.I'd like the number  for channel 11 news,please.
马上挂断电话
Hang up the phone now
我是迈克尔  斯科菲尔德 我在科特贝克旅馆11号房
This is michael scofield.I'm at the cutback motel,room 11.
我要自首
I would like to surrender.
那是什么地方?
Where is that?
那是荷兰
It is Holland.
我长大的地方  你知道的呀
You know that.
那很美
It's beautiful.
这条留言是给玛丽克鲁兹的
This message is for Maricruz.
我会在艾克斯塔帕的机场等你
I'll be there in the airport in Ixtapa waiting for you.
大家好  我叫莎拉 我是个瘾君子
Hi, my name is Sara,and I'm an addict.
你好  莎拉
Hi, Sara.Hi, Sara.(applause)
我只想快点把刑服完 我不想惹任何麻烦
I'm just looking to do my time;I don't any any trouble.
嘿!  住手  犯人!
Hey!Break it up, convict!
不不  这不好笑
No, no, this isn't fun--what was fun
好笑的是当我和卡罗琳在谈论你
was when Caroline and I would talk about you
那个毛头小子迷恋她
and the schoolboy crush that you had on her.
还向她求婚
He proposed to her.
特伦斯!
Hey!Terrence!
我要走!
I'm leaving!
特伦斯  听我说
Terrence, listen to me.
听着
Just listen.
很多人因你遭受了不幸
So many people have suffered because of this, because of you.
当新闻媒体来这的时候 你可以告诉他们真相
When the press get here,you can tell the truth.
你可以结束这一切
You can end this.
对不起了
Sorry.
中断一下节目  插播最新收到的新闻
We interrupt this program for a special news bulletin.
来自于蒙大拿州科特贝克市的爆炸性消息
It's breaking news out of Cutback, Montana.
林肯 布伦斯和迈克尔 斯科菲尔德
Lincoln Burrows and Michael Scofield,
这两名从伊利诺斯州福克斯河 州立监狱越狱出来的囚犯
two of the prisoners who broke out of Fox River State Penitentiary in Illinois
不断给当局留下些蛛丝马迹
have continued to allude the authorities,leaving a trail of crime in their wake.
今天他们留下了些别的东西
And today, they left behind something else.
我是林肯 布伦斯 我是清白的
My name is Lincoln Burrows,and I'm innocent.
六小时前
- 我们完了- 这里没有别的出口
We're done.There's no other way out of here.
下次你决定召开新闻发布会
Next time you decide to hold a press conference,
选个有后门的房间
do it from a room with a back door.
让我想想
Just let me think.
蒙大拿高速公路巡警
MAN (over bullhorn):Montana Highway Patrol.
迈克尔 斯科菲尔德还有林肯 布伦斯
Michael Scofield and Lincoln Burrows,
举起手出来
you'll need to exit with your hands in the air.
再次警告
This is a warning.
举起手出来
Exit with your hands up.
- 他怎么办?- 他还能怎么办? 他已经没有价值了
What about him?What about him?He's useless.
那可是具死尸啊?上面到处是我们的指纹
A dead body?We got fingerprints everywhere.
你是否还担心有人陷害你谋杀罪?
Are you worried someone's gonna pin a murder on you?
那你怎么打算  扔下死尸
So what's your plan,leave the body
- 走正门离开?- 没错
walk out the front door?Yes.
那就是我们要去做的
That's exactly what we're going to do.
迈克尔 斯科菲尔德  林肯 布伦斯
Michael Scofield and Lincoln Burrows,
举起手出来
you need to exit with your hands up.
我是联邦探员  别开枪
FBI. Hold your fire.
联邦探员?
MAN:FBI?
- 开始摄影- 我把布伦斯和斯科菲尔德制服了
Start rolling.I have Burrows and Scofield in custody.
我们出来了  别开枪
We're coming out.Hold your fire.
等等  你是谁?
Hold up, who are you?
联邦调查局探员 我们要去比林斯(美蒙大纳州一城市)
Federal Bureau of Investigation.We're going to Billings.
等一下  再让我看看那证件
Wait a minute,let me see that ID again.
没问题 放下枪!
Okay.Drop the gun!
别这么做!
Don't do it!
大家都别冲动  事情就好办了
Everybody calm down,and this won't get ugly.
好了  你去!
MICHAEL:All right, you!
马上把这两辆警车的钥匙都给我
I want keys to both of cop cars now!
别听他的!去拿钥匙!
Do not do it!Don't listen to him!Get the keys!
- 上车  林肯 - 接下去怎么办?
Linc, get in the car.What's going on?
在有人员伤亡前  我们先离开这
We're getting out of here before anyone else gets hurt.
林肯  发动车吧!去拿钥匙  快点!
Lincoln, start it.Come on! Come on!
呆在那儿  不然我就杀了他
Come on!Stay there or I will drop him.
- 最后的机会了  我不会再说一遍的- 再往前一步我就杀了他
I'm not gonna tell you again.One more step and I drop him.
快啊!
Come on!
开门
Open the door
欢迎归来
LANG:Welcome back.
- 你感觉怎样?- 好多了
You feeling...?Much better.
有什么新消息吗?
Update?
算你说着了
Okay, you got it.
发现了什么线索?
Get a lead on something?
福克斯河监狱的狱警布拉德利 贝利克
One of the COs from Fox River,Brad Bellick,
昨晚被监禁了
got locked up last night
罪名是谋杀另一名警卫
for the murder of another guard.
等等  我们这是要追捕狱警吗?
Wait, we're looking for COs now?
那些逃犯怎么样了?
What about the escapees?
斯科菲尔德?
Scofield?
布伦斯?目前还没有他们的消息
Burrows?Nothing on them currently.
另外  富兰克林的妻子
Also, Franklin's wife...
已经在北达科他州被监管了
(phone rings) was taken into custody
他的妻子?
His wife?
2号线电话
Line two.
我是马宏探员
This is Agent Mahone.
多久前?
How long ago?
我们做个交易吧 你一步不挪的话
I'll make you a deal--if you don't move a muscle,
我就不打爆你头
I won't blow your head off.
格雷格  没人会伤害你
No one's gonna hurt you, Greg.
迈克尔  我们去哪?
Where are we going,
不可能一直这么开下去吧
Michael?Can't keep driving.
我们失去了斯蒂德曼
We lost Steadman.
- 也不知莎拉的下落- 嘘!
Sara's in the wind.Shh!
开响点
Turn it up.
...携带枪支很危险
(over radio):...are armed and dangerous.
布伦斯被判处了死刑
Burrows was sentenced to die
罪名是谋杀总统的兄弟
for the murder of the president's brother.
目前联系不上总统
The president could not be reached
因为她还在继续视察中西部地区 感谢关键州府对她的支持
as she continues to tour the Midwest.
我想要感谢你们每个人
REYNOLDS:I want to thank all of you who
过去以来对我的一贯支持
have supported me in the past,and I appreciate
我对你们来年的继续支持深表谢意
your continued support in the upcoming year.
莱娜斯总统今天将抵达科罗拉多州
REPORTER:Reynolds travels to Colorado tomorrow
出席计划今晚在丹佛举行的见面会
for a scheduled appearance in Denver this evening.
停车
Pull over.
干什么?
What for?
让你停车就停车
Just pull over.
下车
要把那小子扔下车?
Want to drop off this kid?
还不是时候
Later.
我们得把克里曼也甩了
We should get rid of Kellerman, too.
我们不需要他
We don't need him.
事实上我们还需要他
Actually, we do.
我们还有压箱底的宝贝
We still have assets.
关键是我们该如何利用
It's just a question of how we use them.
护士
Nurse.
护士!
Nurse!
你根本不是护士
You ain't no nurse.
你说对了
You right about that.(medical device beeping)
队长  那个打伤的青皮蛋真漂亮
Oh, that's a pretty shineryou got, Captain.
一定会让你想起以前
Must make you think about all the times
身着炫目警服  在这里晃悠的情形
you walked around here in your fancy guard outfit,
而现在这都变成了青皮蛋
turning a blind eye
你看到的一切都是错误的
to everything you saw that was wrong.
谁?我吗?  我什么都知道
"Who me?Oh, I didn't see nothing."
青皮蛋感觉如何?
How that blind eye feel now?
你个王八羔子
You son of a bitch.
你要开始习惯起来
Get used to it.
听说像你这样的老家伙
Hear old one-eyed jack's
会被按上插座操
gonna be getting screwed in the socket.
- 除非我死了- 不必
Over my dead body. No.
死人感受不到被击倒
A dead man can't feel a beat-down.
还会有很多苦头等着你
And you got a lot more coming your way.
好了  我们走
Come on now,let's go.
警察还要花点时间才能找到这
It'll take the feds a while to figure that out.
现在几点了?
What time is it?
刚过9点
A little after 9:00.
时间很紧
It's gonna be tight.
六小时内要赶450里路
450 miles in six hours.
- 你怎么想?- 如果想赶上  现在就要动身
What do you think?Got to move now if we're going to make it.
向前看!
Eyes front.
看看这个
Hey, look at this.
很好  你准备好了吗?
It's perfect. You ready?
是的
Yep.
墨西哥斯纳洛州  15号高速公路
美丽的乡村
没关系
听你的口音
是哪的口音?
波多黎各
Puerto Rico.
墨西哥这块区域的波多黎各人可不多
你要去哪里?
艾克斯塔帕
那很远啊
是的  千里之外
为什么去艾克斯塔帕对你这么重要?那里有什么?
我生命的全部
为了个女人吧
是的  我的女人
在我到那之前，希望他不会走掉
吃吧  拉里  给你的
Here, Larry, that's for you.
这个怎么样
What about this?
太小了点吧
This is too small.
怎么浮不起来?
Why didn't it float?
怎么浮...
Why didn't it...?
我还得要些木头
I need more wood.
木头能浮起来
Wood floats.
这个可以
This will work.
哥们
Hey, man.
能不能给我们来点啤酒
We were just wondering if you could buy us some beer.
行  没问题
Yeah, sure.
能不能也给我的狗来点吃的?
Can I get some food for my dog, too?
悉听尊便  哥们
Do whatever thing you got to do, man.
你干脆自己也来份啤酒吧
You can even keep a beer for yourself.
啊?  不要
Huh? Oh, no.
我爸以前老喝酒
My dad used to drink.
这个你们肯定有兴趣
You're going to want to see this.
我们把蒙大拿中区的所有公路
LANG:We've shut down every freeway
都封锁了
in central Montana.
- 目前为止还没他们的踪迹- 扩大范围
So far, no sign of them. Go wider.
沿着90号和94号公路 直到怀俄明州交界处
Get troopers on and 90 and 94,all the way
全线派兵把守 通知怀特费舍
through Wyoming,and call Whitefish.
让他把15号公路尽头加拿大边境也封掉
Have him lock down the Canadian border at 15.
继续报道本台头条福克斯河八君子事件
REPORTER:Recapping our top story on the Fox River Eight, we will
现在播放一段摄影师遭逃犯绑架后
now bring you exclusive footage shot by
拍下的独家录象
a cameraman who was kidnapped by the escapees.
我是林肯  布伦斯  我是无辜的
My name is Lincoln Burrows,and I'm innocent.
我从福克斯河越狱是因为
I escaped from Fox River Penitentiary
我被冠以一项莫须有的罪名
because I was sentenced to death for a crime
而被判死刑
I did not commit.
我没有杀特伦斯  斯蒂德曼
I did not murder Terrence Steadman.
他昨晚在离蒙大拿不莱克福德的家
He committed suicide last night in the Cutback Motel,
30里外的科特贝克旅店自杀了
30 miles outside of his home in Blackfoot, Montana.
他以死求得不再害怕
He killed himself out of fear.
害怕那些在过去三年
Fear of the people who have been hiding him
软禁他的人
for the past three years.
那帮人就是想害死我哥的人
The same people who want my brother dead.
他们不想你们知道他们是谁 但是听明白了:
They don't want you to know who they are, but know this:
他们盗取了数十亿美金
They've stolen billions of dollars
害死了几十个无辜的人
and murdered dozensof innocent people.
把我们的头像贴上通缉榜
And yet they plaster our faces on the news,
并大肆造谣让你们害怕
and tell you to be afraid.
他们是个跨国公司
They are a group of multinationals
打着合作的幌子
with corporate interests.
他们名义上是个公司
Together, they're known as The Company.
实际上则为政府高层卖命
MICHAEL:They are working with the highest levels of government,
包括美国总统
including the president of the United States.
在这些上头条前立刻封杀
Damage control immediately,before this hits page one.
现在是现场直播啊  长官
It's already airing, sir.
在佛罗里达放把大火!
Start a wildfire in Florida!
要么找个废弃的仓库 关一堆阿拉伯人进去
Find a lost storage unit
管不了那么多了!
full of Arabs!I do not care!
只要别再关注林肯  布伦斯就行!
As long as it's not about Lincoln Burrows!
- 他们不计法律后果- 去啊!
And they operate with impunity Go!
在特勤组的掩护下  他们无法无天
under the cover of the Secret Service,
卡鲁玛奥站到了
保重
谢谢
你也到站了
天下没有免费的午餐  抱歉啦
你不了解 我一定要到艾克斯塔帕去  求你了
你打算找麻烦吗?
会做饭吗?
什么?
我拔毛  我老婆负责烹饪
她已经死了
抱歉老大  我还得赶路呢
那是今天最后一班车了
你要是能把鸡烧好
我就请你过夜
等等
你住这里?
门就在我车的对面
知道吗
我做饭可是绝顶一流的
这边请吧
还有位无辜者卷在其中 她就是莎拉  唐克雷蒂医生
Dr. Sara Tancredi.
知不知道这带子有多少时间?
Do we know how long the videotape lasts?
从头到尾有26分钟
26 minutes, beginning to end.
网上也有了
It's all online.
我知道不能奢求你再给我次机会
I know I can't ask you for another chance.
我现在只希望
I can only hope that,by now,
你能找到安全的避难所
you've found your safe haven.
把字幕录下来
Start a transcript.
每个字都要录
I need every word.
...利用你帮助他人的职责 我却置你于一个
...your commitment to help others, and I put you in a place
对每个医生来说都是噩梦的境地
that's every doctor's nightmare.
我真希望这一切能重新来过...
I wish I could do things differently...
打电话给蒙大拿方面 让他们派人去
Call Montana, have them send an agent to talk
和那个摄影的人谈谈 我想知道他都听见什么看见什么
to the cameraman-- I want to know what he saw, what he heard,
他们穿的是什么--任何可提供的情报
what they were wearing--anything he can give us.
...政府特工出来杀人
...people murdered by government operatives.
一个叫亚历山大  马宏的特工
One man, Special Agent Alexander Mahone,
要对很多起死亡事件负责
is responsible for multiple deaths. He murdered
他不但谋杀了约翰  阿布鲁奇 和大卫  阿克斯
not only John Abruzzi and David Apolskis,
还包括他上一个追捕的逃犯
but also the last fugitive he was assigned to chase:
名叫奥斯卡·沙尔斯
a man named Oscar Shales.
他2年前从监狱里逃走
A man who escaped from prison two years ago,
到现在还是我国的头号通缉犯
who remains one of this country's most wanted
只是他永远也找不到了
despite the fact he will never be found.
这个疯子
The guy's nuts.
他不择手段让死因看起来正常无异
LINCOLN:He'll do whatever it takes to make the deaths look official--
像是在执行公务时候发生似的
like they happened in the line of duty--
失踪  事故......
disappearances, accidents...
- 谢谢- 不客气  给你
Hey, thank you. Sure. Here you go.
你拿木头来干吗?
What's the wood for?
我在造木筏
I'm building a raft.
去荷兰的话我还得再多加些木头
I need more wood if I'm going to make it to Holland.
荷兰?  没错
Holland?Yeah.
你想看看吗?
Want to see it?
木筏
The raft?
你想就用它漂去到荷兰？
GIRL:You're going to try to get from here to Holland in that?
- 没错 - 祝你好运  大傻
Yeah, good luck,Gilligan.
我去撒泡尿
I'm going to take a leak.
你怎么知道往哪个方向走?
How are you going to know where you're going?
你有没有地图之类的东西?
Do you have, like,a map or anything?
有啊
Yeah. I do.
在......
It's-it's right...
在这儿呢
Oh, it's right here.
这是你的地图?
That's your map?
好吧  真希望你能成功
Well, I really hope you make it.
知道么每天早上我醒来
You know, every morning,I wake up
都想知道如果突然消失会怎样
and wonder what it would be like to just disappear.
而你正在这么做呢
And you're just going to do it.
我觉得太了不起了
I think it's great.
好吧
Okay. Well...
你手臂怎么了?
What happened to your arm?
我爸也是个酒鬼
My dad drinks, too.
怎么回事?
What's going on?
- 没事- 不 不  不要.
Oh, nothing. No, no. No, no, don't...
松手
Let me go.
- 我只是想帮你疗伤- 让我走
I just want to fix it.Let me go.
- 不 我只是想...- 住手
No, I just want...Stop!
马特 能带我回家吗?
Matt, will you take me home, please?
不 我
No, I...
神经病
Freak.
布拉德 现在感觉怎么样?
All right, now, Brad,how we doing?
不咋的
I could be better.
皮外伤是不好受
Yeah, that's a nasty contusion,
24小时后就会慢慢消肿下去
but it should go down in about 24 hours.
我拿到把你转移回
I got your paperwork here for your transfer
普通监狱的文件
back to Gen Pop.
已经拿到了?
Already?
移进移出 你知道这里的规矩
Move 'em in, move 'em out;you know the policy.
凯蒂
Katie...
什么事?
Mm-hmm?
你今天看上去真漂亮
You look nice today.
你在这里已经工作了10年多吧?
You worked here over tenyears, right?
差不多吧
Something like that.
我们作为朋友也有些时候了
That's a long time we've been friends.
布拉德 如果你想我用绳子把你
Brad, if you think I can pull some strings to keep you
从牢房里拖出来 我可办不到
out of Gen Pop, I can't do that.
求求你 求你了 你不能再把我送回那鬼地方
Please. Please,You can't send me back there.
难道你不想知道他们 将会如何对我吗?
Do you want that responsibility,knowing what they'll do to me?
让我告诉你  求求你
Just listen, please.
就一个晚上
One more night.
只是让我今晚待在这
Just let me stay here tonight.
我知道你有权这么做
I know you can do that.
当你回家的时候
And when you go home,
只是让门开着就好
just leave that door open for me.
他们在头后面的墙上
(door closes)REPORTER: They hung a sheet
挂了条被单
behind their heads on the wall.
当布伦斯和斯科菲尔德
One of them--
正在讨论关于
the guy with the gun--he found it
他们得跑多远的时候
while Burrows and Scofield were talking
其中一个持枪的家伙发现了被单
about how far they had to go.
斯科菲尔德说了些在6个小时内前进450英里的事情
Uh... Scofield said something about 450 miles in six hours.
450英里到哪去?
450 miles to where?
我不清楚
I don't know.
6个小时内前进450英里
450 miles in six hours.
这条圆弧上的任意一个点
Any point on this circle
都很有可能是他们的最终目的地
could be their final destination.
每小时75英里 外加停车加油
75 miles per hour,stopping for gas.
完全能做到
It's doable.Yeah.
他们现在在哪里?
Where are they?
我还不清楚
I'm not sure.
我还需要点时间
I still need more time.
马宏先生 这一切来得不能再快了
This can't happen fast enough,Mr. Mahone.
他们已经造成了无法挽回的坏印象
They've already done irreparable damage.
斯科菲尔德在日出前不久
Scofield made the video in a storage facility somewhere
在大瀑布城和赫勒拿市之间的
between Great Falls and Helena
某个仓库里录制了那个视频
not long after sunrise.
在那里有目击者听到
From there, the witness said
他们将去450英里远的一个地方
they had 450 miles to get where they were going.
包括西雅图
There's Seattle,
波特兰 盐湖城 丹佛
Portland, Salt Lake, Denver...
丹佛?
Denver?
是的 怎么了?
Yes. What?
总统下午3:00点将在那
The president is speaking there this afternoon.
有个演讲
3:00.
从他们录好视频刚好6个小时
Six hours from when they made the video.
他们在追踪总统
They go in have to president
司法部立即以完全无根据的证据
by escaped convicts Lincoln Burrows and Michael Scofield
为理由不予考虑在逃犯林肯 布伦斯
was immediately dismissed by the Justice Department
和迈克尔 斯科菲尔德的控诉
as entirely baseless, which brings us back to the story
我台将继续一整天的跟进报道
(over radio):we'll be continuing to follow throughout the day.
恐怖威胁警报已经上升为橙色
The terror threat has been raised to Orange
当由几个阿拉伯裔美国人
as a storage unit rented by several Arab Americans
租用的仓库突然...
was suddenly...(radio shuts off)
他们隐瞒了事实 把它从头版上撤掉掩盖掉了
They buried it, dumped it off the front page and buried it.
他们经常这么做
It's what they do.
他们可以任意歪曲是非
They can spin it all they want,
这件事情已经捅出去了
it's out there now.
给他们点时间  录影带会起作用的
Give it time;the tape is going to work.
那娘们就好比圣母玛丽亚 如果我们不能近距离接触她
This is a Hail Mary, man--if we don't get to her...
靠近她并不难
Getting to her is the easy part.
关键是我们之后该怎么做
It's what we do after that's the problem.
这就是为何要速战速决的原因
Which is why this has to happen quickly.
一旦有人知道她在我们手上 事情会水落石出的
Once anyone knows we have her,the curtain comes down.
这样好了 我将会通知 白宫取消总统的这次演讲
Well, I'll notify the White House to cancel the President's speech.
不 如果她的行程路线有一点变化
No. If there's any change to her itinerary,
兄弟俩会发觉有事情要发生
the brothers will know something's up,
他们就会回去继续藏起来
and they're gonna go right back into hiding.
之前我们找到过他们 我们当然还能再找到他们...
We've found them before, we can certainly find them again...
威勒探员 他们可不是傻瓜
These are not pets,Agent Wheeler.
的确是 多谢指教 我对此非常清楚
Yeah, thanks,I'm pretty clear on that,
但是如果你要拿总统作为诱饵的话
but if you're going to use the commander-in-chief
这的确不是什么妙招
as bait, it's certainly not going to...
你对我做事的方法有什么问题吗?
You have a problem with the way that I do things?
的确是这样
Yeah.
并不是只有我一个这么想
And I'm not the only one.
是这样吗?
Is that right?
内务部已经让我从现在起
Internal Affairs has asked me to run all your moves
全权监督你的所有工作
through them from here on out.
那好  拿支笔来
Then get a pen
把你听到的逐字写下来
and make sure you get this word-for-word.
总统今天的行程不会有任何变化
The president's day does not change.
我们唯一掌握的线索
The only lead we have is that
就是他们会去哪里
we know where these men are headed.
所以我们必须静观其变
So we're gonna keep quiet about this
让他们来
and let 'em come.
现在 从我的办公室滚出去
Now, get out of my office.
他们现在是全美国 最容易认出来的两张脸
They're two of the most recognizable faces in America.
他们怎样才能
How do they think they were going to get
近距离地接触到总统呢?
anywhere near the president?
因为他们已经不再只有两个人了
Because it's not just the two of them anymore.
我要再仔细地看看那段视频
I'm gonna go take a closer look at that video.
长官 如果可以
If I may, sir, the president...
你确信我们应当向总统隐瞒这件事?
Are you certain we should keep her in the dark on this?
因为在某些场合
Because there is a scenario where...
她还非常有用
she could be useful.
她已经快触及危机了
It is... her ass on the line, sir.
我认为我们都非常清楚 当危机降临的时候
And I think we're all pretty clear she's been known
她也脱不了干系
to get her hands dirty when that line gets too close.
我们应当让她知道
We should let her know
危机离她有多近
just how close it is.
没带钱要旅行可是件难事
鸡肉好吃么?
我太太做的更好吃
她去世多久了?
一个礼拜
真遗憾
你们结婚多长时间了?
42年了
有什么秘诀么?
你结婚了吗?
没有  希望马上就会结
这可得花一大笔钱啊 结婚这事
谢谢提醒
你在逃避些什么?
是在追求些东西
一个生活在希望上的男人
有希望不好么?
希望是对那些状况不太好的人来说的
在后屋有张床
谢谢
不 得谢谢你
没什么比独自用餐更糟的了  晚安
屋子被他们掩盖的很好
They did a good job masking the room.
没反射 也没反光
No reflections,no flares.
背景声音呢?  可有教堂钟声
Audio markers--church bells,
建筑工地  往来车声等类似线索?
construction, traffic, anything?
从声音来看他们在一个空间较大的地方
The room tone tells us they were in a large space--
大概100000立方英尺
about 100,000 cubic feet.
这么说来那个摄像师说的没错了?
So the kid with the camera--his story matches up?
我们计算了下光照强度
We clocked the quality of light
对应了下时间点
with the time of day,
与他说的时间和地点完全吻合
and it pretty much fits his wheres and whens.
好  里面内容呢?
All right, content.
一些常规的参照物  眼 手 脚
The usual tells--eyes, hands, feet.
我们调出布伦斯案子里的一些记录
Burrows, we were able to baseline him off the footage from his trial,
对比后更加确定这些都是真的
so we got even more clarity there.
我从福克斯河监狱逃出来
I escaped fromfrom Fox River Penitentiary
因为一项莫须有的罪名 我被判死刑
because I was sentenced to death for a crime I did not commit.
我没有谋杀特伦斯  斯蒂德曼
I did not murder Terrence Steadman.
好 这里停下
Okay, there.
看他的眼睛
The eyes.
看到了么?
See it?
稍稍看向左边  然后往上
Yeah, slight shift to the left, then up.
是的  此处眨眼频率比平常高
Yeah, blink rate's up here versus the pattern.
他昨晚在离蒙大拿不莱克福德的家
LINCOLN:He committed suicide last night in the Cutback Motel
30里外的科特贝克旅店自杀了
30 miles outside from this home in Blackfoot, Montana.
他在说谎
He's lying.
像是的
Seems so.
好 这里停下 布伦斯
Okay, here,Burrows,
双手交叉
arms folded.
他在保护自己
He's protecting himself.
他不择手段...
We'll do whatever it takes...
说这些话时不怎么自信
Not a lot of confidence in these words.
...像是在执行公务时候发生似的
...like they happen in the line of duty.
那意味着他在掩饰些什么
Okay, that means something other than what he's saying.
就像我们父亲奥多  布伦斯...
Like our father Aldo Burrows...
体态 肩膀这些是重点
Posture, shoulders in, for emphasis.
多注意这里
Really wants your attention here.
我们的律师维罗妮卡  多诺万...
Our attorney, Veronica Donovan...
- 我在打电话...- 这停下
I was on the phone...Right there.
-...当他们开枪就像射杀动物一样 - 关键点来了
...when they shot her like an animal.Adam's apple.
放大 放大
Zoom in, zoom in.
我们拍这段录像是要让全世界知道
We made this tape to let the world know...
这根本是个谎言
That's a lie.
是的
Yeah.
他的行为很古板
His behavior is textbook.
如果有任何关于他们 去丹佛做什么的情况
If there's anything in here about what they plan on doing in Denver,
他们会说出来的
they're gonna tell us.
如果真这么做  未免太过头了吧
If you say it that way, it plays too earnest.
就是要这么做  因为这是事实
'Course it will--it's the truth.
但是如果这个事实传到百姓耳中
Okay, but the truth sends them home to the wife and kids.
会让所有人都感到不安的
Lies will keep them busy.
我不会向整个国家的人撒谎
I'm not telling a lie to the whole country.
这是我们说出一切的唯一机会...
It's our one chance to say it out...
是的  说你想说的任何事
Yeah, say whatever the hell you want--
告诉他们你是正义使者
tell them you're the Green Lantern--
但我知道他们如何破解录像带的
but I know how they break down these tapes.
因为我曾经做过
I've done it.
任何细节都是很重要的
Every detail matters.
本  拉登把右腿搁左腿上 还是左腿放右腿上
Bin Laden crosses his legs--right over left--
所告诉我们的信息是完全不同的
tells us something completely different than left over right.
这不是一回事
It's not the same message.
对他们来说  这就是
To them, it is.
如果你们想要这个计划成功
If you want this plan to work, whatever you say
那么不管你们说什么
with your mouths, you need to be saying
都要说的与肢体动作和眼神不同步
something different with your bodies and your eyes.
略微向上然后往左看
Slightly up and to the left.
是的
Yes.
许多罪责被枉加于另一名无辜者
Much blame has been placed on another innocent person...
总统的车队已经抵达
LANG:President's motorcade is rolling in.
目前为止没有两兄弟的踪迹
So far no sign of the brothers.
这里  这里
Right there. Right there.
斯科菲尔德手在干什么
What's Scofield doing with his hand?
我们已经放出了一连串重磅炸弹
We've been throwing them a bunch of fast balls.
现在再打乱一下他们的节奏如何?
What do you say we mix it up a little?
比如说?
Like what?
我们估计这是摩尔斯电码
(keys tapping) We think it's Morse code.
表示什么
For what?
目前只知道这条短语是"水热了"
Right now we've got a phrase,"The water is warm."
谁知道这是什么意思?
Any idea what that might mean?
这究竟是什么意思
What the hell does that mean?
什么也不是
Nothing.
但这样做够联邦探员想一阵子的
But it'll take the Feds a while to figure that out.
我们已经派出分队 调查周边城郡的水温
TECHIE: We have teams checking the surrounding counties
可能是给其他同伙的消息
for the water temps. It might be a message to an accomplice.
北普拉特河穿过这个城市
The North Platte river runs through the city.
也许他们设法利用...
Maybe they're trying to use...
这没有任何含义
It doesn't mean anything.
有个家伙跟他一块跑了 那人以前是特勤局的
He's traveling with an ex-Secret Service guy.
我猜测这是故意给我们很多线索
I'm guessing they're spoon-feeding us every lead
好让我们分神去跟进
they want us to follow.
所有举动都是为了分散我们的注意
So all this is just a distraction
从而使他们有时间追踪总统
while they go after the president?
他们早就知道录像会被怀疑
They had to know the tape would be discredited.
他们早就知道我们会找摄影师谈话
They had to know that we'd talk to the cameraman.
许多罪责被枉加于另一名无辜者
Much blame has been placed on another innocent person,
唐克雷蒂 莎拉医生
Dr. Sara Tancredi.
莎拉  如果你在听
Sara, if you're listening,
我知道无法奢求你再给我一次机会
I know I can't ask you for another chance.
现在只希望你能找到安全的避难所
I only hope by now you've found your safe haven.
我利用了你
I took advantage of you,
利用你帮助他人的职责
of your commitment to help others
我却置你于一个 对每个医生来说都是噩梦的境地
and put your in a place that's every doctor's nightmare.
莎拉  如果你在听
Sara, if you're listening,
我知道无法奢求你再给我一次机会
I know I can't ask you for another chance.
现在只希望你能找到安全的避难所
I only hope by now you've found your safe haven.
我利用了你
I took advantage of you,
利用你帮助他人的职责
of your commitment to help others
我却置你于一个 对每个医生来说都是噩梦的境地
and put your in a place that's every doctor's nightmare.
...利用你帮助他人的职责
...of your commitment to help others
我却置你于一个
and put you in a place
对每个医生来说都是噩梦的境地
that's every doctor's nightmare.
我想了很多道歉的方式
I've considered many ways to apologize,
但我必须通过一种来向你道歉
but I must arrive at one.
没有什么不同的
There's more of the same here.
无论是肢体语言还是表达方式
Uh, body language, his tells...
如果你问我  我觉得没什么不一样的
If you ask me, it doesn't look like he means this at all.
我不关心看到什么  再播一遍
I don't care what it looks like.Play it again.
- 我不明白...- 再播一遍
I don't see...Play it again.
现在只希望你能找到安全的避难所
I only hope by now you've found your safe haven.
我利用了你
I took advantage of you,
利用你帮助他人的职责
of your commitment to help others
我却置你于一个 对每个医生来说都是噩梦的境地
and put you in a place that's every doctor's nightmare.
注意他的声音  你有没有觉得
His voice-- would you say
他对那女的语气诚恳
he sounds sincere when he's talking to her
与陈述罪行时有所不同
as opposed to when he's talking about their crimes?
我想你可以这么认为
I... I guess you could say that.
我是这么觉得  你怎么说?
I did say that.Would you say that?
我真希望一切都能重新来过
I wish I could do this differently,
- 但如今太迟了 - 恩
but it's too late for that now.Yeah.
对于你和其他人来说都太迟了
It's too late for you and for others.
人们被政府的特工谋杀
People murdered by government operatives...
这跟特伦斯  斯蒂德曼无关
This isn't about Terrence Steadman,
也跟他们的清白无关
and it's not about their innocence.
- 你什么意思? - 他们不是去找总统
What do you mean? They're not going after the president;
而是为了找到那个医生
they're going after the doctor.
我要所有关于唐克雷蒂 莎拉的资料
I want everything we've got on Sara Tancredi--
朋友  亲戚  笔友
friends, families, pen-pals.
以及任何给她发过谢函的人
If anybody so much as wrote her a thank-you note,
我要知道他们到底在哪  快点!
I want to know where the hell they are now!
你们在哪里找到他的
城南15号路的方向
我们并不认识他但是能认出你的车
我知道了
我很高兴你们能把他带回来
我都没来得及给他加油钱
这么说  你确实借车给他
抱歉
你是否需要警官把车弄回来
不用了  就在不远
他能走过去
去找你的女孩吧
再来寻求宽恕
莎拉  唐克雷蒂
Sara Tancredi.
父母双亡
Dad dead, mom dead.
电子邮箱帐户只有少数联系人地址
E-mail account shows a minimal list of contacts
并且少有来往
with very little activity.
信用卡主要用来支付食品
Credit cards used mostly for groceries,
和零散的一些衣物
sporadic clothing shopping and, uh,
还买过几张单人电影票
the purchase of single movie tickets.
妇产科纪录表明
And ob-gyn records tell us she's had very little in the way
她最近没有任何性关系
of sexual relationships recently.
说实话
To tell you the truth,
我可以说工作就是她生活的全部
I would say the bulk of her life was her work.
对不起先生  你去哪?
Excuse me, sir,where are you going?
很显然  我们干掉的是一名看门者
Apparently,we took out a janitor.
当一切尘埃落定  都会水落石出的
When it all comes down, all of this will get cleared up.
如果我们找不到莎拉 又怎能尘埃落定?
Well, it ain't coming down if we don't get Sara.
她会来这的
She'll be here.
我要跟我弟弟说两句
I want to speak to my brother.
我们要想好
We got to start thinking
如果她没出现应该怎么办
about what to do if she doesn't show.
还有她出现了又该怎么办
Or if she does.
如果那家伙帮助我们
What if the only reason this guy's helping us
就是为了莎拉掌握的信息又该怎么办
is to get whatever information Sara has?
如果这只是一个大骗局呢?
What if this is just one giant setup?
晚安
Well, good night.
你回来得正是时候
It's about time you come home.
你又和那个费帖克出去混了?
Been out with that Feytek boy again?
萨沙
Sasha.
你或许
You may
长得像我...
look like me...
但跟男孩子交往方面 你跟你妈倒是很像
but you take after your mom when it comes to boys,
不是吗?
now, don't you?
希望我品味更好点
Hopefully, with a little better taste.
该死的小姑娘  给我放尊重点
Damn it, girl, you are gonna show me some respect.
我知道莎拉没有什么朋友
I know Sara didn't have many friends.
她可以算是一个孤独的人
She's sort of a loner.
但你是她的朋友
But you were her friend.
我想我应该是吧
I like to think so, yes.
连你也不知道她现在可能在哪儿吗?
And you have no idea where she is now?
不知道
No.
这是斯科菲尔德和布伦斯视频的录音稿
This is a transcript of the Scofield-Burrows videotape.
我把他和莎拉直接对话的部分圈划出来了
I highlighted the part where he talks directly to Sara.
你有什么头绪吗?
Mean anything to you?
没有
No.
如果他曾经有过预谋
You have no idea where she might meet him, if
你也不知道她会在哪里见他?
...that's his plan?
不知道
(sighs):No.
布拉德  贝利克还在这间诊疗室吗?
Is Brad Bellick still here in the infirmary?
是的  怎么了?
Yeah. Why?
你现在肯定很幸灾乐祸
You must be loving this.
我不是开车来这幸灾乐祸的
I didn't drive all this way to gloat.
那么你来做什么?
Well, then what the hell you come here for?
首先我真的要向你致敬
(sighs)First, I really...got to tip my cap to you.
你曾经把矛头直指哪些罪犯
You've managed to draw a bead on the convicts
要比我的手下还要勤快
more often than my own staff.
也真谢谢你那么尽责了  但...
Well, thanks for the "attaboy," but...
但你也知道
as you can see,
这样的司法体系看不到你的怜悯
the correctional system doesn't share your gratitude.
我不会占用你很长时间 但我有几个问题要问
I won't take much of your time,but I do have a few questions.
- 关于什么的?- 莎拉  唐克雷蒂
About...? Sara Tancredi.
在她的工作申请书中
She listed you as a reference
他把你列为了推荐人
on her job application to work here.
你很了解她么?
You know her well?
如果你能把我调到隔离监狱 我对她的了解会更深
I'd know her a lot better if you can get my ass moved to Ad Seg.
我在监狱部门没有影响力
(chuckles softly)I have no influence
这你是知道的
with the D.O.C.--you know that.
但如果你想要我的帮助 你一定可以办到
If you want my help, you do.
我会跟狱长商量看看能帮上什么
I'll talk to the warden and see what I can do--
只要你给我需要的答案
right after you give me some answers.
斯科菲尔德喜欢通过 加密信息来和莎拉交流
Scofield likes to communicate with Sara via coded message.
你能解读这些信息吗?
Do you recognize anything here?
- 他在试图告诉她什么?- 不知道
Anything that he may be trying to tell her? No.
我只知道他在向莎拉道歉
I mean, he's saying he's sorry.
而这对冷面大夫一点好处都没有
Not that that's gonna do any good with Dr. Cold Shoulder.
但是...
But...
什么?
What?
隔离监狱
Ad Seg.
我知道了
Yeah.
好吧  你来看看
All right, you see here,
他说道"另一次机会"
where it says this stuff about "another chance."
"安全避难所"
"Safe haven."
这都是出自一本有名的书里
That's out of the big book.
什么书?
What big book?
"酗酒无名氏"
Alcoholics Anonymous.
莎拉正在恢复中
Sara's in recovery.
- 这我知道 - 这些名字他都是取自
Yeah, I'm aware of that.Those are the names
那本书的章节名
of some of the chapters in the book they use in AA.
你有"酗酒无名氏"这本书吗?
Do you have a copy of the Alcoholics Anonymous book?
莎拉  如果你在听的话
MICHAEL: Sara, if you're listening,
我知道不能奢求你"再给次机会"
I know I can't ask you for another chance.
我现在只希望 你能找到"安全的避难所"
I can only hope by now you've found your safe haven.
我利用了你帮助别人的承诺
I took advantage of you, your commitment to help others
我却置你于一个 对每个医生来说都是噩梦的境地
and put you in a place that's every doctor's nightmare.
我想过很多道歉的方式
I've considered many ways to apologize,
但我必须通过一种来向你道歉
but I must arrive at one.
- 天色晚了- 我知道
It's getting late.I know.
她还没来
She's not here.
这我也知道
I know that, too.
有可能她没有收到消息
There is a chance she didn't get the message.
或许她对这一切都已经厌烦了
Or maybe she's just sick of all this.
忘了在基拉时  她背叛了你
The girl bailed on you back in Gila.
你凭什么觉得她会回心转意?
What makes you think she's gonna come running back now?
就凭着支持了我们三个月的东西
The same thing that's been keeping us going
信念
for the last three months:faith.
但现实会让信念消失的
Yeah, well... reality's kicking faith's ass, man.
再等等吧
Look...Wait, wait.
等?  老弟  我们不能再等下去了
Wait? Man, we can't wait anymore.
请注意  再次呼叫迈克尔  克莱恩 (注：克莱恩暗指为折纸仙鹤)
(over P.A. system):Once again, Michael Crane,Listen, listen.
请你到前台
please report to the front desk.
你有电话
You have a telephone call.
迈克尔  克莱恩请到前台
Michael Crane to the front desk.
是的  莎拉  唐克雷蒂
Yeah. Sara Tancredi.
对  有可能她现在和他们在一起
That's right. She might be with them now.
对! 通知阿克隆地区的警方
Just... Yes! Just call the local police
通知他们调集所有人手
in Akron and tell them to get everyone they have
现在马上赶去圣托马斯医院
over to St. Thomas Hospital now.
我是迈克尔  克莱恩 应该有个我的电话
Michael Crane. I think you have a call for me.
谢谢
Thank you.
我是克莱恩
This is Mr. Crane.
这比"Origami"(日语  折纸鹤)要好听
It sounded better than "Origami."
即使你收到消息了 我都不确定你是不是会回复
Even if you got the message, I wasn't sure you'd respond.
我不能及时赶到你这儿了
I-I couldn't get to you in time.
这是我唯一想得到的
This is the only thing I could think of.
我发誓我会离开你 但我不得不联系你
I swore I'd leave you alone, but I had to contact you.
因为我有什么东西么?
Because I have something?
你怎么知道?
How'd you know?
迈克尔  在基拉的时候 我的确要回到你身边的
Michael, back in Gila I was coming back to you.
但有人抓住了我
Somebody... grabbed me, and they, um,
我们告诉我父亲给了我些东西
they told me that my father had given me something.
他们伤着你了?
Did someone hurt you?
我逃走了
I-I got away.
迈克尔  我希望这一切都能结束
Michael, I want for this to be over.
我们两个都这样希望
That makes two of us.
你认为这可能吗?
Do you think that's possible?
如果有你的帮助  一定可以
With your help, yes.
问题就在于你能不能看到
It's just a question of looking
你父亲留给你的财富
at whatever it is your father gave you.
这只是...
It's just...
这只是一把钥匙啊
It's just a key.
我们会弄清楚的
Well, we'll figure it out.
我们一起
Together.
我喜欢你这么说
I like the sound of that.
我也是
Me, too.
你好  保罗
Hello, Paul.
总统女士  有段时间没看到你了
Madam President, it's been a while.
我知道
I know.
我打电话来道歉的
I'm calling to apologize.
好吧
Okay.
我非常抱歉
I'm so sorry
一切都离我而去 可我最终却伤害了那个
It all just got away from me, and I ended up hurting
一直陪伴我左右的人
the one person who's always been at my side.
我希望你能回来  保罗
I want you to come home, Paul.
我们能够解决这个问题的
We can fix this.
我们一起
Together.
而不是和那两个满世界逃亡
But not with those brothers running around the country
搞垮在你帮助下建立起的公司的人
tearing down the very office you helped me build.
卡罗琳...
Caroline...
抓他们回来吧 保罗
Bring them in, Paul, and everything can go back
这样一切都可以回到原来的状态
to the way it was.
我得走了
I have to go now.
我们尽快再联系
I'll see you soon.
你和莎拉谈过了吗?
Did you talk to Sara?
几天之内  不管是好是坏
In a few days, this should all be over,
这一切都会结束了
one way or the other.
当然
Absolutely.